overlandingafrica.com 2019-12-25

# Privacy policy - Discover Africa | Discover Africa Safaris

## Keep reading for detailed full privacy policy.

## **For your quick reference, we've noted our stance on some of the most important privacy issues:**

  * We will never share your personal information with any third party.
  * We will never send you spam.
  * If you do opt-in to receive emails from us, you will be able to opt-out via our website at any time.

## **What information do we collect?**

We collect information from you when you register on our site, place an order, subscribe to our newsletter or fill out a form.

When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your: name, e-mail address, mailing address or phone number. You may, however, visit our site anonymously.

Like most websites, we use cookies and/or web beacons to enhance your experience, gather general visitor information, and track visits to our website. Please refer to the 'do we use cookies?' section below for information about cookies and how we use them.

## **What do we use your information for?**

Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways:

  * To personalise your experience (your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs)
  * To improve our website (we continually strive to improve our website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you)
  * To improve customer service (your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs)
  * To process transactions
  * To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site features
  * To send periodic emails

Your information, whether public or private, will not be sold, exchanged, transferred, or given to any other company for any reason whatsoever, without your consent, other than for the express purpose of delivering the purchased product or service requested.

The email address you provide for order processing, will only be used to send you information and updates pertaining to your order.

If you decide to opt-in to our mailing list, you will receive emails that may include company news, updates, related product or service information, etc.

Note: If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email.

## **How do we protect your information?**

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you place an order.

We offer the use of a secure server. All supplied sensitive/credit information is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our Payment gateway providers database only to be accessible by those authorised with special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential.

After a transaction, your private information (credit cards, social security numbers, financials, etc.) will not be stored on our servers.

## **Do we use cookies?**

_For the purpose of this document, cookies can also refer to local storage or other web beacons.  _

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computers hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the sites or service providers systems to recognise your browser and capture and remember certain information.

We use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart, understand and save your preferences for future visits and compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

If you prefer, you can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies via your browser settings. Like most websites, if you turn your cookies off, some of our services may not function properly. However, you can still place orders over the telephone or by contacting customer service.

## **Do we disclose any information to outside parties?**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

## **Third party links**

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

## **Privacy Policy - Analytics + Remarketing**

Discover Africa adheres to a strict privacy policy for the protection of our users. 

We guarantee that personal information provided by the user will be employed solely for the purpose of providing any service that the user has requested. 

We guarantee that no user data, personal or otherwise, will ever be passed to external agencies or third parties for any reason unless required by law. 

Please note that we advertise on third party sites through Google AdWords, and Google may use cookies to serve ads based on your visit to this site. 

You may opt out of seeing ads for this site by visiting the [Google advertising opt-out page](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html "Google Opt-out Page"). 

In addition, Discover Africa uses Google Analytics to monitor website activity. For more information on how Google collects and processes data please see [How Google Uses Data When You Use Partner Sites Or Apps](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/).

## **California Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance**

Because we value your privacy we have taken the necessary precautions to be in compliance with the California Online Privacy Protection Act. We therefore will not distribute your personal information to outside parties without your consent.

## **Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance**

We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act), we do not collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older.

## **Online Privacy Policy Only**

This online privacy policy applies only to information collected through our website and not to information collected offline.

## **Terms & Conditions**

Please also visit our Terms and Conditions section establishing the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing the use of our website at http://www.discoverafrica.com/terms/

## **Your Consent**

By using our site, you consent to our online privacy policy.

## **Changes to our Privacy Policy**

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page, and/or update the Privacy Policy modification date below.

This policy was last modified on  **1 August 2011**.

## **Contacting Us**

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us using the information below.

Tel: +27 (0)21 423 1912  
Website: http://www.discoverafrica.com

38 Hout Street  
Cape Town  
8001  
South Africa

PO Box 31147  
Tokai  
7966  
South Africa

[http://www.discoverafrica.com/contact/](http://discoverafrica.com/contact/) to contact us by email.
